Rob Strasser

Software Engineer

robstrasserdev@gmail.com • (925) 549-1803 • https://robstrass.github.io/

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 2 years as a Software Engineer with startups & a global insurance company

TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Express, Node is, GraphQL, React Native, Jest, Redux Languages PostgreSQL, auth0, Git, Azure DevOps, JIRA, NSX, MaterialUI, CosmosDB, Docker Tools

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BoomNation Remote (Birmingham, AL)

Software Engineer 1 11/2023-02/2024

Technologies: Javascript, React, React Native, Node is, GraphQL, Express, PostgreSQL, Jest

- Part of a 3 person engineering team that collaborated closely with Product, Marketing, and C-Suite to plan and deliver product features and updates on a consumer-facing app with over 250,000 users in an Agile setting
- Refactored payment pipeline for self-checkout to integrate new pricing models and tier features table leading to a 19% increase in client acquisition
- Built a new mobile login flow resulting in a 25% increase in user signups and a 40% increase in user profile completions by converting a multi-step process into a single-page long-form
- Laid off as part of the reduction of staff due to lack of a successful funding round

Remote (London, UK) Munich Re

Software Engineer 1, Network Automation (Contract)

02/2023 - 11/2023

Technologies: TypeScript, JavaScript, CosmosDB, Azure DevOps, NSX, vRealize, Postman

- Part of a 5 person team in a contract role delivering internal tooling to facilitate Network Automation workflows, serving 40,000+ employees, releasing weekly or bimonthly updates in a CI/CD cycle on a codebase with over 113,000 lines of code
- Built a workflow leveraging multiple APIs to automate the process of cleaning the database, NSX environments, and vCenters of network segments and virtual machines, reducing manual efforts from 1-3 days to 1-hour maximum
- Patched, tested, and re-developed 12+ automation workflows delivered in a non-functioning state by an external team, identifying dozens of critical bugs that would have brought down Production or left internal applications vulnerable
- Collaborated with 20+ people from 3 different teams spread across the UK, Germany, and Moldova, overcoming time differences of 8-10 hours, to overcome barriers and achieve project goals by identifying key decision-makers and project owners within the organization
- Performed code reviews for 5+ team members on at least a weekly basis, ensuring strict code standards and company policies were met while also personally accounting for 2-4 items per release
- Contract ended due to EOY budget constraints

SPJ Solutions Remote (Sacramento, CA) 04/2022 - 01/2023

Software Engineer 1

Technologies: Typescript, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, NSX, Postman

- Part of a 15+ person Agile startup development team building an application that managed the migration of clients' networking environments, handling the migration of 5000+ virtual machines, serving 100+ clients
- Appointed sole developer of large micro-segmentation feature that took a snapshot of clients' existing network environment's firewall, organizing and deploying migration in 8 steps to the latest version of NSX
- Developed an algorithm to sort and order 4,000+ firewall rules decreasing manual organization by 90%
- Laid off as 1 of 10 employees following company restructuring

2017-2021: Asset Protection Supervisor, team of 8 employees. SDR, met 120% of quota. Learned client leadership & time management

EDUCATION & ACCREDITATIONS

App Academy Coding Bootcamp CSU East Bay - BS Criminal Justice 07/2021 - 01/2022

09/2013-06/2017